well this song has a lot of meanings for
me I think even the most obvious meaning
when you first listen to it and when we
were writing it was to create a song
about how you love is the most
intoxicating powerful drug in the world
it can just make you feel so high that
you don't even realize that you're in a
relationship that's not really real that
it wasn't really love it all
it was just a perfect illusion you know
our modern struggle with a you know
human connection when it comes to you
know social media and the sort sort of
endless running of images on instagram
and twitter and other social media where
were all kind of creating these perfect
illusions of ourselves that were either
trying to keep up with or maybe having
trouble keeping up with other people's
illusions and unable to find what's
authentic in the sea of all of that so
you know this song is about all of those
things
well Josh worked on guitars and that
happened a little bit later
kevin was the sort of the brainchild of
the record he really was the one that
came up with the concept of illusion and
he came in with these like melodies and
lyrics ideas and we sat down and we kind
of tore it into sections and we wrote
came up with the concept of illusion and
he came in with these like melodies and
lyrics ideas and we sat down and we kind
of tore it into sections and we wrote
the lyrics and melodies and restructured
of the chorus the sentiment of the
chorus and took the song to a new place
it was really important to me that the
song wasn't just about any illusion it
had to be about the one that fires up
the most you know what is the illusion
that people nowadays feel the most kind
of knocked down by and you know we
ultimately thought it was the perfect
the most you know what is the illusion
that people nowadays feel the most kind
of knocked down by and you know we
ultimately thought it was the perfect
ones that are just so good that you a
full the hell out of you
flood pops an incredible producer Mark
Ronson you know executive produced the
whole album and he's just brilliant and
very generous of imeem I think the
coolest thing about it was being
embraced as a female musician
you know it was just um I was treated so
equally in the studio and it really
helped me to you know game even more
confidence and create something i'm
really proud of with my friends
well mark and I have known each other
for almost 10 years so I already knew
him I met Kevin through mark because
they worked together and I i know i met
blood pop then threw John genic from
interscope father john misty I met
through genetic as well but I knew all
of these people I just was being
connected to them now for the first time
through mutual friends back is someone
through genetic as well but I knew all
of these people I just was being
connected to them now for the first time
through mutual friends back is someone
who I adored and loved for a very long
time it was this secret to him that I
was a big fan so I I like hunted him
down at the samurai show and was like we
need to write songs and he came in and
worked with us as well and Florence i've
known and i asked her to write with me
and she wanted to and we work this great
song he girl together i mean i could go
on and on it's just a wonderful
wonderful group of people and I'm i was
really lucky every time you finish a
song he girl together i mean i could go
on and on it's just a wonderful
wonderful group of people and I'm i was
really lucky every time you finish a
record or you finished writing a song
there's that moment where everyone kind
of looked at each other and goes oh my
god thats that's a record that sounds
like a great record and it's a it
there's no it there's no feeling like it
i mean i remember just the other day
here's one I was I walked into the
nightclub moth in London to sing perfect
illusion for the first time and I hadn't
seen mark since the song went to number
one on iTunes in over 60 countries and I
just walked into the DJ booth and looked
at it and we just stared at each other
for a few seconds and we're just silent
because you know that what do you say
because at the end of the day we're just
two kids from New York we just can't
believe our songs on the
radio and I'd also say that did I I'm
made dinner for the guy's a lot at the
studio I would cook and you know at five
o'clock we pour a drink and I go in and
heat up all the food that I would make
in the morning at my place and then
bring over and possums little kitchen at
the studio so we would you eat kind of
like a family and eat home-cooked food
and then we would work again late into
the night and I just won't forget that
it was just such an awesome you know
family feeling it was just a deeper and
it was more emotional it was a little
bit more difficult for a lot more
difficult at times
mark was really great at navigating that
because you know i could be quite
emotional at a point trying to get out
lyrics and get out melodies and get out
idea that you just try to calm me down
and you know remind me that my
perspective of as an artist is important
that I don't try to be anything but
myself and you know having someone to
reaffirm the things that you believe in
is really important and i would also say
that it's even hard now even doing
interviews about this album removed
today is so much harder than doing all
the other interviews about the other
albums i've done before because they're
more concept records and the themes on
them were you know related to fame or
four born this way it was you know more
of a social activism and related to
bullying and acceptance and
individuality and what it's like to grow
up then like an outcast and artpop was a
lot more are a conceptual artistic album
bullying and acceptance and
individuality and what it's like to grow
up then like an outcast and artpop was a
lot more are a conceptual artistic album
and then you have this new one and it's
it's just you know a bunch of songs
about my life so as I'm telling each
interviewer about the record I'm delving
into these private stories that are you
know they're just like right at the
surface you know especially since i'm
still finishing things up i'm like a I
tell everyone I'm a laugh away from atty
like I could laugh really loud or cry at
you know in a second
你也可以在网易云音乐搜索“希言电台”收听本视频的纯音频。